<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ben Marwick on Ben Marwick</title>
    <link>/bmarwick/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ben Marwick on Ben Marwick</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/bmarwick/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Statement of professional values, ethics, and expectations</title>
      <link>/bmarwick/values_and_ethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bmarwick/values_and_ethics/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-of-conduct-for-the-uw-geoarchaeology-laboratory-and-field-research-projects&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct for the UW Geoarchaeology Laboratory and Field Research Projects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This document is primarily aimed at graduate students pursuing a PhD or masters degree. Some sections are also relevant to undergraduates, please ask if you have questions about what parts are appropriate to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;purpose&#34;&gt;Purpose&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This document should be viewed as a tool to initiate discussion during the early stages of the graduate program, with an awareness that the relationship and expectations will evolve with time. The parties may wish to use this template not only for verbal discussion but also as a written letter of understanding that will help to guide the relationship and expectations  of the student, their PI, and the relevant departments/faculties. The hope is that this agreement clarifies questions that arise in the lab setting and reduces conflict or tension to make everyone’s interactions more enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-uw-geoarchaeology-laboratory-and-ben-marwick-s-field-research-projects-are-committed-to-an-harassment-free-policy&#34;&gt;The UW Geoarchaeology Laboratory and Ben Marwick&amp;rsquo;s Field Research Projects are committed to an harassment-free policy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We value the participation of every member of our community and want to ensure that every member has an enjoyable and fulfilling learning and working experience. Accordingly, everyone who participates is expected to show respect and courtesy to other participants at all times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make clear what is expected, all participants (including myself) must conform to the following Code of Conduct:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ben Marwick, as head of the UW Geoarchaeology Laboratory and director of field research projects, and participants, are dedicated to a harassment-free experience for everyone, regardless  of gender, gender identity and expression, sexual orientation, disability, physical appearance, race, national origin, age or religion. We do not tolerate harassment by and/or of members of our community in any form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In summary:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All communication – online and in person – should be appropriate for a professional audience including people of many different backgrounds.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sexual language and imagery is not appropriate at any time.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be kind and respectful to others and their opinions.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not insult or put down other lab members. Your ideas are not more valuable than others&amp;rsquo;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Behave professionally.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remember that harassment and sexist, racist, or exclusionary jokes will not be tolerated in this space.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Participants asked to stop any harassing or disrespectful behavior are expected to comply immediately.
Participants who violate these rules – no matter how much they have contributed to the UW Geoarchaeology Laboratory or field research projects, or how specialized  their skill set – will be approached by Ben Marwick. If inappropriate behaviour persists after a discussion with Ben Marwick, the perpetuator will be asked to discontinue their participation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To report violation, you can do any of the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please feel free to talk to me if the violation is perpetuated by any other participant that is not myself&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Report to the the &lt;a href=&#34;https://anthropology.washington.edu/contact&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Chair of the Anthropology Department&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make an anonymous report and get advice from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.washington.edu/safecampus/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;UW SafeCampus Office&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;responsibilities-for-graduate-and-undergradute-students-working-with-me&#34;&gt;Responsibilities for Graduate and Undergradute Students working with me&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;as-a-graduate-student-it-is-your-responsibility-to&#34;&gt;As a graduate student, it is your responsibility to:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete your degree. This includes classroom and laboratory work, which have to be conducted with professionalism, self-motivation, engagement, scientific curiousity, and high ethical standards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be knowledgeable of the policies, deadlines, and requirements of the graduate program, the graduate school, and the university. Comply with all institutional policies, including academic program milestones, laboratory practices, and rules related to chemical safety, biosafety, and fieldwork.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work with me to develop a thesis project for your degree. Your degree requires that you produce a coherent body of research representing a contribution to your scientific field. Ensure that your research is ultimately proceeding towards this goal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be responsive to advice and constructive criticism. The feedback you get from me, your colleagues, your committee members, and your course instructors is intended to improve you. Provide feedback on my mentoring to you. Not everyone has the same mentoring needs and personalities, so there will inevitably be places where my efforts do not line up with your preferences. I am not infallible, but can only make adjustments when I know that they are needed.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;as-an-undergraduate-student-doing-independent-research-with-me-it-is-your-responsibility-to&#34;&gt;As an undergraduate student doing independent research with me, it is your responsibility to:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commmunicate often. This includes face-to-face meetings, email and other methods. I expect to hear from you in some way every week. Reach out with questions as soon as they pop up. Send a follow-up message if I don&amp;rsquo;t reply in three days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set specific goals. We will discuss the overall objective of your research, and we will negotiate how to divide this up into smaller tasks. You will organise your time to accomplish these tasks, and communicate with me if there are unexpected changes to your schedule.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take detailed notes. Keep a record of your work in a place we can both see it, such as a Google Doc or on GitHub. Update your notes weekly or more often.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Participate in the UW Undergraduate Research Symposium. This is an excellent way to show the results of your efforts in a way that your friends and family can enjoy also.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be responsive to advice and constructive criticism. The feedback you get from me and your course instructors is intended to improve you. Provide feedback on my mentoring to you. Not everyone has the same mentoring needs and personalities, so there will inevitably be places where my efforts do not line up with your preferences. I am not infallible, but can only make adjustments when I know that they are needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;as-a-pi-it-is-my-responsibility-to&#34;&gt;As a PI, it is my responsibility to:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Provide everyone under my supervision an environment that is safe and free of harassment, intellectually stimulating, and emotionally supportive.&lt;/strong&gt; I will enforce a culture governed by collegiality that values differences in personalities and opinions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be committed to your research project.&lt;/strong&gt; I will help you design an independent project within the scope of the lab&amp;rsquo;s research for your thesis, or other work. I will be intellectually committed to your research. This includes helping you to generate experimental and theoretical ideas, interpreting and constructively criticizing your data and contextualizing it within a broader context, and supporting you in presenting your ideas and results to the scientific community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ensure that you receive appropriate training.&lt;/strong&gt; I will provide resources and mentorship from both myself and senior lab members so that you have the technical skills that you need to accomplish your research. If the training you need does not fall within the lab&amp;rsquo;s expertise, we shall discuss opportunities for you to receive that training elsewhere, either through collaborations with other laboratories or by attending workshops and classes outside of this University.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lead by example and facilitate your training in complementary skills needed to be a successful scientist&lt;/strong&gt;, such as oral and written communication, applying for grants, lab management, mentoring, and scientific ethics and professionalism. I will encourage you to seek teaching opportunities, even if not required for your degree, include you where appropriate in grant writing and manuscript reviews, and provide opportunities for you to mentor junior researchers. I will enforce high standards of scientific ethics and professionalism.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Provide financial resources to you as appropriate and according to this institution&amp;rsquo;s guidelines.&lt;/strong&gt; To the best of my ability, I will provide the resources that you need to conduct your experiments. In addition, I will support you in trying to obtain external funding for your degree program.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Help you navigate your graduate program of study.&lt;/strong&gt; You are responsible for keeping up with deadlines and being knowledgeable about requirements for your specific program. However, I am available to help interpret these requirements, select appropriate coursework, and select committee members for your oral exams.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Help you build your professional social networks, including presenting at scientific meetings.&lt;/strong&gt; I will attempt, as funding allows, to send you to a major conference every year when you have material to present. I will also help you to identify and apply for travel fellowships to help pay for attending these conferences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Provide career advice and assist you in finding a position following your graduation.&lt;/strong&gt; I will give advice and feedback on your career goals, and encourage you to explore opportunities both outside and within academia as suits your interests and progress. I will promptly provide honest letters of recommendation whenever they are requested of me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;accommodations-for-students-with-disabilities&#34;&gt;Accommodations for Students with Disabilities&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For students with disabilities or specific medical needs, we will meet to discuss what accommodations should to be made to your work schedule or lab responsibilities to facilitate your productivity in the lab without compromising on your physical or mental health. If changes in your needs occur over time, we will meet again to revise this accommodation. I promise to prioritize your health for the good of the lab community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;lab-meetings&#34;&gt;Lab meetings&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lab meetings will occur weekly, unless interrupted by a reseach meting or a holiday. Attendance is required and it is important that you come prepared when it is your turn to share. I will notify you of changes to the schedule at least a day in advance. In addition, I will meet individually with graduate students on a weekly basis to discuss progress and help when needed. The timing of these meetings may change depending on projects, pending publications, and your graduate defense. We will address this as needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;lab-documents&#34;&gt;Lab Documents&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is your responsibility to maintain a detailed, organized, and accurate record of your research. Lab notebooks are lab property and therefore must be maintained to a standard where they can be interpreted by others. Any computer code that you generate must be properly documented and archived to ensure its reproduciblity not only by others, but also by yourself when time passes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;data-and-code-management&#34;&gt;Data and code management&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the best of our ability, we practice open science; the default is set to &amp;lsquo;open&amp;rsquo;. All of your code will be published alongside manuscripts. All raw data, metadata, analyzed data, figures, and code developed in the lab to accompany published papers are required to be freely available online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;presentations&#34;&gt;Presentations&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under my guidance, you are expected to be able to present your work in department seminars and external meetings as soon as you begin generating data. We also encourage blogging and open discussion of research on social media. You will engage fully in the scientific program of the conferences that you attend. You should aim to present at program and departmental seminars 1-2 times per year in addition to attending one scientific conference per year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;manuscripts&#34;&gt;Manuscripts&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on your experience and level of comfort with writing a scientific manuscript, my level of engagement related to writing will change. It is often the case that the first manuscript is written largely by the PI and/or by any other more senior author who had contributed to the study, with lots of input from you, the trainee and first author of the manuscript. You will, for instance, be asked to make figures, help outline the flow, and edit the text. However, I expect you to be largely responsible for the writing of a second manuscript. Manuscripts should include a paragraph at the end of the methods section with the heading &amp;ldquo;Reproducibility and Open Materials&amp;rdquo; that gives the DOI to the reader can find the code and data used to produce the figures, tables, and statistical results presented in the paper. It should also give the licences used for those materials (e.g. MIT for code, CC-BY for figures, CC-0 for data)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;time-off&#34;&gt;Time Off&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I expect you to be productive in your research and the other elements of your graduate program (teaching etc.). How you achieve this is ultimately up to you and should be customized to fit your working style. If you or I feel like you are not progressing adequately, you or I should discuss the situation and work together to find a more suitable and productive working schedule. Vacations and work-life balance are important for creative thinking and good health. However, please consult with me before making plans, and understand that some activities are time-sensitive (e.g., sampling, preparing for grants, manuscripts, exams, or conferences). I am also certainly willing to accommodate sick and/or parental leave as required, and will determined this on a case-by-case basis. Before I take a vacation, I will provide the lab with at least one week notice so that we can all work around my absence without loss of productivity. When I am on vacation, I prefer to be contacted via email in the case of lab-based emergencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;career-development&#34;&gt;Career Development&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is your responsibility as a graduate student to actively cultivate your professional development in non-research contexts. Becoming a successful scientist requires more than just academic research. You are expected to continually develop as a teacher, as a scientific ambassador to the general public, and your scientific network. This may include taking advantage of professional programs offered through the university, active participation in external seminars, attending classes without direct applications to your research, conferences, workshops, and membership in professional societies. If your participation in a career-building course, program, or event requires you to reduce your time spent by lab, we will discuss it on a case-by-case basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;flexible-working-hours&#34;&gt;Flexible working hours&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I may be sending this email outside my normal office hours, I have no expectation to receive a reply outside yours. The hours that members of the lab choose to work is up to them. We are each welcome to send work-related emails or communications over the weekend or late at night, but no lab members are required to reply to them outside of their typical work hours. Lab members are welcome to work flexibly for any reason. Ideally, all lab members will have at least a few hours each week to overlap with Ben in order to stay in touch on any challenges or successes, but it is the policy of the  Lab that every member is already self-motivated and doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to work a traditional 9 to 5 day in order to meet their goals. If you experience any challenges related to flexible working within the lab please contact Ben Marwick. All communication will be treated as confidential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;field-research-expectations-for-students&#34;&gt;Field research expectations for students&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Archaeological fieldwork can be exciting as well as physically and mentally challenging. My fieldwork is often in remote locations with limited access to clean water, electricity, internet connectivity, and comfortable places to sit or sleep. Despite these conditions, it can be great fun, and an excellent learning experience. For undergraduate and graduate students, if you are joining me in the field  expect you to be ready learn new things. I expect you to be ready to be involved in all relevant field research activities. When communicating with me and others under difficult conditions I encourage you to use appropriate humour, use a positive, optimistic framing, and assume there will be a good outcome. Plans and conditions can change rapidly during fieldwork: I expect you to be open to many possibilities and to the exploration of options. We strongly value team work in the field. I expect you to take a collaborative approach to solving problems encountered in the field: use &amp;lsquo;we&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;us&amp;rsquo; more than &amp;lsquo;I&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;me&amp;rsquo; when discussing field research activities. If you are not comfortable in any situation at all, for any reason at all (for example, you feel you are not properly equipped or prepared, or you feel you are in danger), I expect you to tell someone immediately so we can help you. For graduate students, I expect you to be involved in post-excavation research, publication, and other opportunities following the conclusion of the fieldwork, unless we have discussed this prior to you joining me in the field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;publishing-ethics&#34;&gt;Publishing Ethics&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important that all authors on a paper deserve the credit. I follow the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.icmje.org/recommendations/browse/roles-and-responsibilities/defining-the-role-of-authors-and-contributors.html#two&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ICMJE guidelines&lt;/a&gt; and use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.casrai.org/credit.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CRediT&lt;/a&gt; (Contributor Roles Taxonomy) for determining when co-authorship is warranted. I encourage my students to use these guidelines when working with others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;reviewing-ethics&#34;&gt;Reviewing Ethics&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my peer reviews of scholarly literature I follow the guidelines of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opennessinitiative.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Peer Reviewers&amp;rsquo; Openness Initiative&lt;/a&gt;. I encourage my students to use these guidelines when doing their own peer reviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;acknowledgements&#34;&gt;Acknowledgements&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The text here is based on Daniela Saderi&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dasaderi/Lab_CoC_templates/blob/master/template_v1.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct for Resaerch Laboratories&lt;/a&gt;, which credits the Freeman Lab Manifesto, the Klassen Lab Mentoring Expectations for Graduate Students, and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/WhitakerLab/WhitakerLabProjectManagement/blob/master/CODE_OF_CONDUCT.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Kirstie Withaker Lab Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. It also borrows from Corina Logan&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://corinalogan.com/ethics.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Lab Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;, and Titus Brown who cites the original source and credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://2012.jsconf.us/#/about&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://2012.jsconf.us/#/about&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; The Ada Initiative. Please help by translating or improving: &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/leftlogic/confcodeofconduct.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://github.com/leftlogic/confcodeofconduct.com&lt;/a&gt;. This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 Unported License&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;further-reading-on-codes-of-conduct&#34;&gt;Further reading on Codes of Conduct:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clancy, K. B. H., Nelson, R. G., Rutherford, J. N., &amp;amp; Hinde, K. (2014). Survey of Academic Field Experiences (SAFE): Trainees Report Harassment and Assault. PLOS ONE, 9(7), e102172. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0102172&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0102172&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meyers, M et al. (2014) What Happens in the Field? Preliminary Results of the SEAC Sexual Harassment Survey. Poster presented at the Southeastern Archaeological Conference, Retrieved January 8, 2019, from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.southeasternarchaeology.org/wp-content/uploads/SEAC-2014-Sexual-Harassment-poster-Meyers-et-al.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.southeasternarchaeology.org/wp-content/uploads/SEAC-2014-Sexual-Harassment-poster-Meyers-et-al.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Miller, Alison (2018, December 6). In some disciplines, heavy drinking is part of the culture. That can be a problem. Science doi:10.1126/science.caredit.aaw3020, Retrieved January 8, 2019, from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencemag.org/careers/2018/12/some-disciplines-heavy-drinking-part-culture-can-be-problem&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.sciencemag.org/careers/2018/12/some-disciplines-heavy-drinking-part-culture-can-be-problem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Muckle, Robert (2014) On Sexual Harassment And Abuse In Archaeology.  The SAA Archaeological Record November 2014, p 32-33, Retrieved January 8, 2019, from  &lt;a href=&#34;http://onlinedigeditions.com/publication/?i=232900#{%22issue_id%22:232900,%22page%22:34&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://onlinedigeditions.com/publication/?i=232900#{%22issue_id%22:232900,%22page%22:34&lt;/a&gt;}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perry, Sara (2018, May 4) Six Fieldwork Expectations: Code of conduct for teams on field projects. The Archaeological Eye (Blog post). Retrieved January 8, 2019, from   &lt;a href=&#34;https://saraperry.wordpress.com/2018/05/04/fieldwork-code-of-conduct/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://saraperry.wordpress.com/2018/05/04/fieldwork-code-of-conduct/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Register of Professional Archaeologists Code of Conduct:
Sexual Harassment. Retrieved January 8, 2019, from  &lt;a href=&#34;http://rpanet.org/?page=RPACodeSexualHarassm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://rpanet.org/?page=RPACodeSexualHarassm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Southeastern Archaeology (2017) SEAC Task Force on Sexual Harassment and Assault Report and Resources.  Retrieved January 8, 2019, from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.southeasternarchaeology.org/sexual-harassment-task-force/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.southeasternarchaeology.org/sexual-harassment-task-force/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
