<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ben Marwick</title>
    <link>/bmarwick/</link>
      <atom:link href="/bmarwick/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Ben Marwick</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/bmarwick/img/portrait.jpg</url>
      <title>Ben Marwick</title>
      <link>/bmarwick/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/bmarwick/values_and_ethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/bmarwick/values_and_ethics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;script src=&#34;https://hypothes.is/embed.js&#34; async&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On these pages I have documented some of my professional values, expectations, and ethics. I post these documents here, in public, so current and prospective students can know what to expect in my classes, lab, and field research. I also want to share with the broader research community what I believe to be the best practices for common professional activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of having these documents is to help us transparently and openly manage our expectations. This make it easier for us to enjoy our learning and research work, while minimizing misunderstandings and bad assumptions. If you are a student, these are the documents that we start with when we discuss our expectations in greater detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the content is adapted from the sources acknowledged below, so these are mostly professional norms in adademia that are typical and widely held. Although not of the content here is original, it does truly express my values, ethics and expectations, and I refer to these documents regularly when working with students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- You can highlight and annotate the text on these pages by selecting it. We can view all public annotations here: https://hypothes.is/search?q=url%3Ahttp%3A%2F%2Ffaculty.washington.edu%2Fbmarwick%2F* --&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;acknowledgements&#34;&gt;Acknowledgements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The text here includes material from:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/neurosarda&#34;&gt;Daniela Saderi&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dasaderi/Lab_CoC_templates/blob/master/template_v1.md&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct for Research Laboratories&lt;/a&gt;, which credits the Freeman Lab Manifesto, the Klassen Lab Mentoring Expectations for Graduate Students, and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/WhitakerLab/WhitakerLabProjectManagement/blob/master/CODE_OF_CONDUCT.md&#34;&gt;Kirstie Withaker Lab Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/LoganCorina&#34;&gt;Corina Logan&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://corinalogan.com/ethics.html&#34;&gt;Lab Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ctitusbrown&#34;&gt;Titus Brown&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://ivory.idyll.org/lab/coc.html&#34;&gt;Lab Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://ivory.idyll.org/lab/philosophy.html&#34;&gt;Lab philosophy&lt;/a&gt;, who cites the original source and credit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://2012.jsconf.us/#/about&#34;&gt;http://2012.jsconf.us/#/about&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&#34;https://adainitiative.org/&#34;&gt;The Ada Initiative&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mariam_s_aly&#34;&gt;Mariam Aly&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; lab manual: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/alylab/labmanual&#34;&gt;https://github.com/alylab/labmanual&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-018-06167-w&#34;&gt;commentary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/maureenritchey&#34;&gt;Maureen Ritchey&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; lab manual: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/memobc/memolab-manual&#34;&gt;https://github.com/memobc/memolab-manual&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jonathanpeelle.net/&#34;&gt;Jonathan Peelle&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; lab manual: &lt;a href=&#34;http://jpeelle.net/peellelab_manual.pdf&#34;&gt;http://jpeelle.net/peellelab_manual.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ArchaeologistSP&#34;&gt;Sara Perry&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://saraperry.wordpress.com/2018/05/04/fieldwork-code-of-conduct/&#34;&gt;Code of conduct for teams on field projects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://history.ecu.edu/jennifer-mckinnon/&#34;&gt;Jennifer F. Mckinnon&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/326426337_Fieldwork_Expectations_Agreement&#34;&gt;Fieldwork Expectations Agreement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://csl.cofc.edu/documents/study-strategies/communication/Effective%20Communication.pdf&#34;&gt;The Seven C’s of Communication&lt;/a&gt; from the College of Charleston Center for Student Learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 Unported License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- add section on TA --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>/bmarwick/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/bmarwick/privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terms</title>
      <link>/bmarwick/terms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/bmarwick/terms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Courses</title>
      <link>/bmarwick/courses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/bmarwick/courses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In addition to teaching these classes I am also the coordinator of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://depts.washington.edu/anthweb/undergrad/tracks-options/archaeological-science&#34;&gt;Archaeological Sciences Option&lt;/a&gt;. This is a transcripted sequence of classes recommended to students who are interested in an in-depth study archaeological methods and theories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;archy-109-archaeology-in-film&#34;&gt;ARCHY 109 Archaeology in Film&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deals with depictions of archaeology by and for non-archaeologists and implication of those depictions at the intersection of archaeology, the human past, and popular culture. 5 credits, I&amp;amp;S&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;archy-270-field-course-in-archaeology&#34;&gt;ARCHY 270 Field Course in Archaeology&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduction to field acquisition of archaeological data through survey and excavation. On-going field projects; recovery and recording techniques. 12 credits, I&amp;amp;S&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;archy-299-archaeological-laboratory-techniques&#34;&gt;ARCHY 299 Archaeological Laboratory Techniques&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laboratory procedures geared to one specific archaeological research project. Prerequisite: either ARCHY 105 or ARCHY 205. 1-3, max. 12 credits, I&amp;amp;S&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;archy-309-archaeology-of-mainland-southeast-asia&#34;&gt;ARCHY 309 Archaeology of Mainland Southeast Asia&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Covers the archaeology of mainland Southeast Asia from the first colonization by hominins to the appearance of written texts, especially in Thailand, Cambodia, Laos, Vietnam, and Myanmar. Emphasizes methods of acquiring archaeological data and addressing current controversies about mainland Southeast Asia prehistory. Prerequisite: ARCHY 205.  5 credits, I&amp;amp;S. Archaeological Sciences non-core class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;archy-319-archaeology-of-australia&#34;&gt;ARCHY 319 Archaeology of Australia&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Archaeology of Australia with an emphasis on understanding of the evidence and interpretation of both singular events and long-term processes in prehistory. Prerequisite: ARCHY 205. 5 credits, I&amp;amp;S. Archaeological Sciences non-core class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;archy-482--486-geoarchaeology-lab--seminar&#34;&gt;ARCHY 482 &amp;amp; 486 Geoarchaeology Lab &amp;amp; Seminar&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lab &amp;amp; seminar on the identification, analysis, and interpretation of sediments and soils associated with archaeological remains. Covers geomorphology, geochemistry and geophysics in archaeology. Prerequisite: ARCHY 205. 3 &amp;amp; 3 credits. Archaeological Sciences core class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;archy-499-undergraduate-research&#34;&gt;ARCHY 499 Undergraduate Research&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advanced laboratory procedures geared to one specific archaeological research project. Prerequisite: ARCHY 205. 5-6, max. 12 credits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;archy-509-archaeology-and-explanation&#34;&gt;ARCHY 509 Archaeology and Explanation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Analytical, historical and quantitative examination in archaeology and philosophy of science. Prerequisite: permission of instruction. 5 credits&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information about current offerings in the archaeology program, see the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.washington.edu/students/crscat/archeo.html&#34;&gt;UW ARCHY course catalog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>/bmarwick/post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/bmarwick/post/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/bmarwick/publication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/bmarwick/publication/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Geoarchaeology Program</title>
      <link>/bmarwick/geoarchaeology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/bmarwick/geoarchaeology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The program here at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.washington.edu/&#34;&gt;University of Washington&lt;/a&gt; is primarily a doctoral program in archaeology, with an emphasis in geoarchaeology for those that wish to pursue it. We believe firmly that geoarchaeology is really archaeology using adaptations of techniques and methods. Thus, the geoarchaeologists that come from this department examine archaeological questions by looking at sedimentological, stratigraphical, petrographic (mineralogy and petrology), geomorphological, and pedologic techniques. We are really doing archaeology, with a geological orientation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;History&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The geoarchaeology program at UW was founded by Julie Stein, who taught the first class here in 1981 and is now the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.washington.edu/burkemuseum/info/welcome.php&#34;&gt;Director of the Burke Museum&lt;/a&gt; and no longer working with students. Julie was a student of George (Rip) Rapp, Herb Wright and Patty Jo Watson and is best known for her work on shell middens in the Pacific Northwest. Julie&#39;s contributions to the interdisciplinary field of archaeological geology were recognised in 1999 when she was awarded the Rip Rapp Archaeological Geology Award (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.geosociety.org/&#34;&gt;Geological Society of America&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://rock.geosociety.org/arch/&#34;&gt;Archaeological Geology Division&lt;/a&gt;).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The geoarchaeology course at UW&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The geoarchaeology course I teach is based on Julie Stein&#39;s curriculum and aims to give students an understanding of the application of geological approaches to archaeological problems. This course also provides a foundation of basic geoarchaeological lab skills to prepare students for advanced research. The course covers stratigraphic, sediment and soil nomenclature used in geoarchaeology, reviews different geomorphologic contexts of archaeological site location and formation and surveys applications of geophysical and geochemical techniques in archaeology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Geoarchaeology in the UW graduate program&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the first two years in the graduate program, all archaeology graduate students are &lt;a href=&#34;https://depts.washington.edu/anthweb/programs/grad_req.php&#34;&gt;required&lt;/a&gt; to take a similar set of courses. Depending on the student&#39;s background (how much statistics and anthropology they have had) some classes may differ. The basic classes are four laboratory classes (bones, ceramics, lithics, and of course geoarchaeology) , two or three theory classes, a quantitative methods class, and thematic and regional classes. These courses prepare students for taking the comprehensive exam that must be taken at the beginning of the seventh quarter in residence (the beginning of Autumn quarter two years after arriving). The exam is difficult and most students take some of spring quarter and most of the summer to prepare. Passing the &lt;a href=&#34;https://depts.washington.edu/anthweb/programs/grad_req.php&#34;&gt;comprehensive exam&lt;/a&gt; is the requirement for receiving a master&#39;s degree. We also require that you write some sort of research report involving an original piece of research. But after the comps are passed you are done with the official requirements for the masters degree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Related courses&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although we do not require that geoarchaeology students have geology or pedology courses before they are admitted, after the comprehensive exams these students should expect to take at least three of the following geoscience courses (Stratigraphy, Depositional Environments, Great Geological Issues, Fluvial Geomorphology, and Geological Time) and 3 pedology courses (Soil Genesis and Classification, Field Survey of Wildland Soils, and Forest Soil Fertility and Chemistry). If you are interested in mineralogy and petrology, then optical mineralogy and work with SEM and ICP is also recommended. Students work with me to design their programs to fit individual needs and backgrounds. This program thus afford a student great flexibility, but only after they have received a heavy dose of basic archaeological theory and practical laboratory knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Geoarchaeology Lab&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://depts.washington.edu/geoarc/&#34;&gt;Geoarchaeology Laboratory&lt;/a&gt; in the department is set up to do basic chemistry, particle size analysis, and thin-section preparation. For detailed chemical work a partnership with the sediment labs in other locations has been negotiated. This arrangement allows students access to better equipment. For example, we have a partnership with &lt;a href=&#34;http://depts.washington.edu/mse/&#34;&gt;Materials Science&lt;/a&gt; to use their thermal analyzer and X-Ray diffraction equipment. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.geophys.washington.edu/&#34;&gt;Earth and Space Sciences&lt;/a&gt; allows students access to their sample preparation facilities, particle size analysers and isotope equipment. As the number of geoarchaeology students grow, the demand for our laboratory equipment increases and necessary arrangements are made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Funding&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of our graduate students receive some sort of &lt;a href=&#34;https://depts.washington.edu/anthweb/programs/grad_fellowship.php&#34;&gt;financial assistance&lt;/a&gt; or apply for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.washington.edu/students/osfa/&#34;&gt;financial aid&lt;/a&gt; in the form of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.washington.edu/students/osfa/ugaid/uw.workstudy.positions.html&#34;&gt;work-study positions&lt;/a&gt; that allow students to work in our labs. The Work-Study applications must be filed in the Spring in the year before new students arrive. However, the funds are small and competition for them is great. Please discuss with me opportunities for financial assistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Quaternary Research Center&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://depts.washington.edu/qrc/&#34;&gt;Quaternary Research Center (QRC)&lt;/a&gt; here at the University of Washington is not a degree-granting department. It is a research center. Although you cannot receive a degree from the QRC, it offers many opportunities such as scholars participating in QRC seminars and lecture series. This research center gives our students exposure to the newest ideas, and collegial contacts. Obviously the QRC is a benefit to anyone interested in geoarchaeology, but not part of the official program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Prospective students&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;d like more information about graduate study in geoarchaeology at UW, you can easily contact me using the form below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&#34;fa-ul&#34; itemscope&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;
         &lt;i class=&#34;fa-li fa fa-comments-o fa-2x&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
         &lt;form action=&#34;https://formspree.io/bmarwick@uw.edu&#34; method=&#34;POST&#34;&gt;
            &lt;label for=&#34;name&#34;&gt;Your name: &lt;/label&gt;
            &lt;input type=&#34;text&#34; name=&#34;name&#34; required=&#34;required&#34; placeholder=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
            &lt;label for=&#34;email&#34;&gt;Your email:  &lt;/label&gt;
            &lt;input type=&#34;email&#34; name=&#34;_replyto&#34; required=&#34;required&#34; placeholder=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
            &lt;label for=&#34;message&#34;&gt;Your message:&lt;/label&gt;&lt;br&gt;
            &lt;textarea rows=&#34;4&#34; name=&#34;message&#34; id=&#34;message&#34; required=&#34;required&#34; class=&#34;form-control&#34; placeholder=&#34;I&#39;m interested to do a PhD in geoarchaeology...&#34;&gt;&lt;/textarea&gt;
            &lt;input type=&#34;hidden&#34; name=&#34;_next&#34; value=&#34;/html/thanks.html&#34; /&gt;
            &lt;input type=&#34;submit&#34; value=&#34;Send&#34; name=&#34;submit&#34; class=&#34;btn btn-primary btn-outline&#34;&gt;
            &lt;input type=&#34;hidden&#34; name=&#34;_subject&#34; value=&#34;Website message&#34; /&gt;
            &lt;input type=&#34;text&#34; name=&#34;_gotcha&#34; style=&#34;display:none&#34; /&gt;
          &lt;/form&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
