<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homes on Ben Marwick</title>
    <link>/bmarwick/home/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homes on Ben Marwick</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/bmarwick/home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ben Marwick</title>
      <link>/bmarwick/home/hero/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bmarwick/home/hero/</guid>
      <description>The highly flexible website framework for Hugo with an extensible plugin mechanism. Create a beautifully simple site in under 10 minutes 🚀 Latest release  
(function defer() { if (window.jQuery) { jQuery(document).ready(function(){ GetLatestReleaseInfo(); }); } else { setTimeout(function() { defer() }, 50); } })(); function GetLatestReleaseInfo() { $.getJSON(&#39;https://api.github.com/repos/gcushen/hugo-academic/tags&#39;).done(function (json) { let release = json[0]; // let downloadURL = release.zipball_url; $(&#39;#academic-release&#39;).text(&#39;Latest release &#39; + release.name); }); }  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/bmarwick/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bmarwick/home/about/</guid>
      <description>About me I am an Associate Professor of Archaeology. My other local affiliations include the eScience Institute, the Burke Museum, the Center for Statistics and Social Sciences, the Quaternary Research Center, and the Southeast Asia Center.
 My main research activities combine models from evolutionary ecology with analyses of archaeological evidence to investigate past human behaviour. Specific interests include hominin dispersals into mainland Southeast Asia, forager technologies and ecology in Australia, mainland Southeast Asia and elsewhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>/bmarwick/home/posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bmarwick/home/posts/</guid>
      <description>19 Aug 2019 How to make the data and code for your manuscript available to peer reviewers before making it public. Blog post for Cambridge University Press on the Cambridge Core Blog. It’s no surprise to any internet user that the way we communicate is rapidly changing. For example, in the distant past, we learned the news of the world by reading a few paragraphs of tiny text in hard copies of newspapers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviews and media mentions</title>
      <link>/bmarwick/home/press/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bmarwick/home/press/</guid>
      <description>18 Jun 2019 A “petting zoo for code” makes studies easier to reproduce: A new tool helps users to compose, compute and publish reproducible articles. by Jeffrey M. Perkel, published in Nature Index. &amp;ldquo;The result, says Ben Marwick, an archeologist and reproducibility advocate at the University of Washington in Seattle, who has used Code Ocean to publish his computing environments, is like a computational “petting zoo” &amp;ndash; a platform for making code and data available to the scientific community for interactive exploration, validation and modification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/bmarwick/home/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bmarwick/home/publications/</guid>
      <description>2019 Marwick, B. L. Wang, R. P. Robinson, H. Loiselle (2019) How to use replication assignments for teaching integrity in empirical archaeology. SocArXiv pre-print socarxiv:tsxbv
Schmidt, S. and B. Marwick (2019) Tool-driven Revolutions in Archaeological Science. SocArXiv pre-print socarxiv:4nkxv
Gray, C. T. and B. Marwick (2019) Truth, Proof, and Reproducibility: There&amp;rsquo;s no counter-attack for the codeless arXiv preprint arXiv:1907.05947
Marwick, B. and L. Wang (2019) How to align disciplinary ideals with actual practices: Transparency and openness in archaeological science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geoarchaeology</title>
      <link>/bmarwick/home/geoarchaeology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bmarwick/home/geoarchaeology/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The program here at the University of Washington is primarily a doctoral program in archaeology, with an emphasis in geoarchaeology for those that wish to pursue it. We believe firmly that geoarchaeology is really archaeology using adaptations of techniques and methods. Thus, the geoarchaeologists that come from this department examine archaeological questions by looking at sedimentological, stratigraphical, petrographic (mineralogy and petrology), geomorphological, and pedologic techniques. We are really doing archaeology, with a geological orientation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>/bmarwick/home/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bmarwick/home/teaching/</guid>
      <description>In addition to teaching these classes I am also the coordinator of the Archaeological Sciences Option. This is a transcripted sequence of classes recommended to students who are interested in an in-depth study archaeological methods and theories.
ARCHY 109 Archaeology in Film Deals with depictions of archaeology by and for non-archaeologists and implication of those depictions at the intersection of archaeology, the human past, and popular culture. 5 credits, I&amp;amp;S</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/bmarwick/home/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bmarwick/home/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>